Records, 1886-1928 and undated
Smithsonian Institution Archives
- Incoming and Occasional Outgoing Correspondence (after 1910), 1886-1928. Arranged alphabetically and in most instances chronologically thereunder., Series 1
  - Box 18
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson (1888-1913). Includes proposed investigations and authorization for expeditions; appointments to the USDA; report, notebook of expenses, and other material regarding trip to Mexico (1897). (Box 18 of 44)
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson (1912). Material regarding Kansas trip. (Box 18 of 44)
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson (1897-1908, 1918). Contains itinerary and journal for Rose's expeditions to Ecuador and Mexico (see also Coulter and Rose). (2 folders) (Box 18 of 44)
  - Box 19
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson. Untitled article written in Spanish - "Botanical Field Expedition in the State of Queretaro"; miscellaneous materials. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson (1908 and undated). Includes notes, lists and Excerpts concerning the administration and space needs of the National Herbarium. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Rosendahl, C. O. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Rost, E. C. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Rothert, W. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Runyon, Robert (Box 19 of 44)
    - Rusby, Henry Hurd (1893-1927) (Box 19 of 44)
    - Russell, Paul G. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Ruth, Albert (Box 19 of 44)
    - Rydberg, Per Axel (1894-1919) (Box 19 of 44)
    - S (Box 19 of 44)
    - Safford, William Edwin (c. 1910-1918) (Box 19 of 44)
    - Sandberg, J. H. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Sargent, Charles Sprague (1892-1911) (Box 19 of 44)
    - Sargent, Oswald H. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Saur, Belden C. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Scheuber, Emma W. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Schoolcraft, Mrs. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Schumann, K. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Schutze, Dr. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Schwarz, Theodore (Box 19 of 44)
    - Seaton, Henry E. (1891-1893) (Box 19 of 44)
    - Setchell, William A. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shantz, H. L. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shaw, Charles H. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shaw, George R. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Sheldon, Edmund P. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shepard, C. Antoinette (Box 19 of 44)
    - Short, Charles Wilkins (1883). Includes a biography on Short and the portion of his will consigning his collection of dried plants to the Smithsonian. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Short, John W. (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shreve, Forrest (1907-1924) (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shriver, Howard (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shull, George Harrison (1902-1910) (Box 19 of 44)
    - Shull, J. Marion (Box 19 of 44)
  - Box 20
    - Simpson, J. H. (1898-1911) (brother of Charles Torrey Simpson) (Box 20 of 44)
    - Slater, Elsie McElroy (Box 20 of 44)
    - Small, John Kunkel (1893-1912, 1927) (Box 20 of 44)
    - Smith, Benjamin H. (Box 20 of 44)
    - Smith, Charles L. (Box 20 of 44)
    - Smith, Herbert H. (Box 20 of 44)
    - Smith, Jared G. (Box 20 of 44)
    - Smith, John Donnell (1891-1906) (4 folders) (Box 20 of 44)
  - Box 21
    - Smith, John Donnell (1907-1927) (2 folders) (Box 21 of 44)
    - Smith, William Wright (Box 21 of 44)
    - Somes, M. P. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sonne, C. F. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sornberger, J. D. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Spalding, V. M. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sprague, T. A. (1926) (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sprenger, Carlo (Box 21 of 44)
    - Standley, Paul Carpenter (1907-1911) (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stanton, T. W. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stearns, Elmer (1904-1912) (Box 21 of 44)
    - Steele, E. S. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Steele, W. C. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stevens, F. L. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stevenson, E. D. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stevenson, Matilda Coxe. Contains SI Registrar office material (1897). (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stiles, W. A. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stivers, Lena H. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stockberger, W. W. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Stokes, Susan G. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sudworth, George B. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Suksdorf, Wilhelm N. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sutton and Sons (Box 21 of 44)
    - Swingle, Walter Tennyson (1905-1923) (Box 21 of 44)
    - Sydow, P. (Box 21 of 44)
    - T (Box 21 of 44)
    - Taubert, P. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Taylor, Elfreda Bennett (Box 21 of 44)
    - Taylor, Norman (Box 21 of 44)
    - Tays, Eugene A. H. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Thackery, Frank A. (Box 21 of 44)
    - Tharp, B. C. (Box 21 of 44)
  - Box 22
    - Thomas-Duris, G. (1913-1924) (Box 22 of 44)
    - Thompson, Charles Henry (1903-1911) (Box 22 of 44)
    - Thornber, J. J. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Thurow, F. W. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tidestrom, Ivan (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tilden, Josephine E. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tonduz, Ad. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Toumey, J. W. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Townsend, Charles H. Tyler (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tracy, S. M. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tradescantia correspondence (1897) (Box 22 of 44)
    - Trask, Blanche (Box 22 of 44)
    - Trelease, William (1891, 1895-1912, 1924) (2 folders) (Box 22 of 44)
    - True, Rodney H. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tschermak, E. von (Box 22 of 44)
    - Turckheim, H. von (Box 22 of 44)
    - Tweedy, Frank (Box 22 of 44)
    - U (Box 22 of 44)
    - Ule, E. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Uline, Edwin B. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Umbach, L. M. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Underwood, Lucien M. (1892-1906) (Box 22 of 44)
    - Urban, Ignatius (1886-1927) (Box 22 of 44)
    - Urbina, Manuel (Box 22 of 44)
    - V (Box 22 of 44)
    - Vail, Anna Murray (Box 22 of 44)
    - Van Dyk, A. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Vaupel, F. (Box 22 of 44)
    - Very, C. F. (Box 22 of 44)
  - Box 23
    - W (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wabash College Honorary Degree (1925). Includes Rose's speech regarding the class of 1885. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Walcott, Charles D. (1911-1927) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Warner, Marjorie F. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Watson, Sereno (1889-1890) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Webber, Herbert John (1900-1902) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Weberbauer, A. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Weeks, George F. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Weigel, Theodor Oswald (Box 23 of 44)
    - Weinberg, Frank (1903-1911) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Weingart, Wilhelm (1923-1924) (in German) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Werckle, C. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wetmore, Alexander (1926). In regard to having Rose ship specimens to Nathaniel Lord Britton through administrative channels; William Ralph Maxon appears to handle administrative tasks. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Whorf, Edward H. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wibbe, J. Herman (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wight, W. F. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wilcox, G. B. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wilcox, Timothy E. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Willey, Henry (1899-1901) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Williams, R. O. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Walcott, Henrietta L. T. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wolthuys, J. J. Verbeek (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wood, J. Medley (Box 23 of 44)
    - Woodward, Robert S. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wooton, Elmer O. (1898-1911) (Box 23 of 44)
    - Wurzlow, H. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Young, R. A. (Box 23 of 44)
    - York, Harlan H. (Box 23 of 44)
    - Y-Z (Box 23 of 44)
- Official Outgoing Correspondence, Joseph Nelson Rose, 1894-1909, 1911-1912. Bound and indexed., Series 2
  Outgoing letterpress correspondence, January 1, 1894-December 30, 1909; July 18, 1911-May 30, 1912. Indexed. 28 volumes. Volumes 1-4 contain correspondence from Joseph Nelson Rose's years with the United States Department of Agriculture. Volumes 5-27, and 30, cover Rose's work with the United States National Herbarium, United States National Museum, Division of Plants. Correspondence includes National Herbarium reports and letters and memoranda from Frederick Vernon Coville, honorary curator, USNH, and William Ralph Maxon, assistant curator, Division of Plants. For general contents regarding the material, see the descriptive entry at the beginning of the finding aid. Letterpress correspondence corresponds to the incoming correspondence, series 1.
  - Box 24
    - January 1, 1894-April 18, 1896 (3 volumes) (Box 24 of 44)
  - Box 25
    - April 20, 1896-December 30, 1897 (3 volumes) (Box 25 of 44)
  - Box 26
    - January 4, 1898-December 22, 1899 (3 volumes) (Box 26 of 44)
  - Box 27
    - December 22, 1899-December 30, 1902 (3 volumes) (Box 27 of 44)
  - Box 28
    - January 1, 1902-July 1903 (3 volumes) (Box 28 of 44)
  - Box 29
    - July 1, 1903-October 10, 1904 (3 volumes) (Box 29 of 44)
  - Box 30
    - October 11, 1904-March 5, 1906 (3 volumes) (Box 30 of 44)
  - Box 31
    - March 5, 1906-November 6, 1907 (3 volumes) (Box 31 of 44)
  - Box 32
    - July 30, 1908-December 30, 1909; July 18, 1911-May 30, 1912 (not inclusive) (3 volumes) (Box 32 of 44)
- Miscellaneous Outgoing Correspondence, 1894-1919 and undated., Series 3
  - Box 33
    - Miscellaneous Contributions to USNH (c. 1903-1908) (Box 33 of 44)
    - Letters salvaged from water soaked letterpress (Box 33 of 44)
- Manuscripts and Correspondence Related to Joseph Nelson Rose and John Donnell Smith Research Project on the Hauya, 1911-1912., Series 4
  This series includes the Joseph Nelson Rose and John Donnell Smith manuscript, "A Monograph of the Hauyeae and Gongylocarpeae Tribes of the Onagraceae," which was published in 1913. There are also letters (1911) and other material between Rose and Smith regarding their project, including a Smith letter to Rose (January 20, 1912) showing his interest in Rose's suggestion that they collaborate on a revision of the genus Hauya. Also included is correspondence between Rose, Richard Rathbun, and William deC. Ravenel of the USNM regarding the project and correspondence with Smith and a manuscript concerning Burragea (1911-1912).
  - Box 33
    - Joseph Nelson Rose and John Donnell Smith. Hauya manuscript. (Box 33 of 44)
    - Joseph Nelson Rose and John Donnell Smith. Hauya correspondence. (Box 33 of 44)
    - Joseph Nelson Rose and John Donnell Smith. Burragea items. (Box 33 of 44)
- Joseph Nelson Rose and Nathaniel Lord Britton Project on Cactaceae, 1919-1923; Rose's Work on Cacti, 1903-1922., Series 5
  This series includes correspondence and memoranda of Rose regarding the four-volume publication The Cactaceae by Rose and Britton along with preparation and publication of the work, reviews, and receipt of the publication by various persons. Also included are passports enabling Rose to go on expeditions for his projects and the text of a speech by Rose, "The Cactus and Its Environmental Relations," 1922. Correspondents include William Barnum, Alwin Berger, Nathaniel Lord Britton, John Merle Coulter, A. L. Herrera, G. L. Machintach, Daniel Trembly MacDougal, John C. Merriam, John Donnell Smith, W. Gilman Thompson, F. Vaupel, Charles D. Walcott, and Robert S. Woodward.
  - Box 33
    - A-Z (Box 33 of 44)
    - Barnum, William (Box 33 of 44)
    - Berger, Alwin (Box 33 of 44)
    - Britton, Nathaniel Lord (Box 33 of 44)
    - Carnegie Institution (Box 33 of 44)
    - Coulter, John Merle (Box 33 of 44)
    - Herrera, Alfonso L. (Box 33 of 44)
    - MacDougal, Daniel Trembly (Box 33 of 44)
    - Mackintosh, G. L. (Box 33 of 44)
    - Merriam, John Campbell (Box 33 of 44)
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson (Box 33 of 44)
    - Smith, John Donnell (Box 33 of 44)
    - Thompson, W. Gilman (Box 33 of 44)
    - Vaupel, F. (Box 33 of 44)
    - Wabash College (Box 33 of 44)
    - Walcott, Charles D. (Box 33 of 44)
    - Woodward, Robert S. (Box 33 of 44)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Memoranda, Expenditures and Liabilities, Manuscripts and Notes, and Annual Reports, 1896-1969., Series 6
  - Box 34
    - Expenditures and Liabilities (1898-1910) (2 folders) (Box 34 of 44)
    - Correspondence (Box 34 of 44)
    - Correspondence B-W (Box 34 of 44)
    - Memoranda and Correspondence (Box 34 of 44)
    - Correspondence B-UV (Box 34 of 44)
  - Box 35
    - Field Photographs (Box 35 of 44)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence A-R (1940-1955) (6 folders) (Box 35 of 44)
  - Box 36
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence S-Z, (1940-1955) (4 folders) (Box 36 of 44)
    - Correspondence (Box 36 of 44)
    - Expenditures and Liabilities (1904-1907) (2 folders) (Box 36 of 44)
  - Box 37
    - Expenditures and Liabilities B-W (1904-1907) (Box 37 of 44)
    - Committee of the Botanical Society of America (1898-1902) (Box 37 of 44)
    - Annual Reports - Department of Botany (1950-1958) (Box 37 of 44)
    - Annual Statement of Exchange Accounts, United States National Herbarium (1933-1946) (Box 37 of 44)
    - Reading File - Department of Botany (1968-1969) (Box 37 of 44)
  - Box 38
    - Administrative Assistant, Expenditures and Liabilities (1902-1904) (Box 38 of 44)
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson. Letters of the National Museum B-L (1902-1904). (Box 38 of 44)
    - Rose, Joseph Nelson. Letters of the National Museum M-W (1902-1904). (Box 38 of 44)
    - Miscellaneous Items (Box 38 of 44)
    - Annual Reports (1922-1929) (1 volume) (Box 38 of 44)
  - Box 39
    - Miscellaneous Notes of George Vasey (1884) (Box 39 of 44)
    - George Vasey. Botanical Gazette: volume 9 (1884), volume 11 (1886), volume 16 (1891); Bulletin of the Torrey Botanical Club: volume 11 (1884), volume 13 (1886), volume 14 (1887), volume 15 (1888) (Box 39 of 44)
    - Walker, E. H. Correspondence (1929-1933, 1940-1943, 1949, 1953) (Box 39 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Notes and reports (1931-1935). (2 folders) (Box 39 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Division of Plants, personal correspondence. (Box 39 of 44)
    - Leonard, Emery C. (1922-1928) (1 volume) (Box 39 of 44)
  - Box 40
    - Maxon, William R. Correspondence on the destruction of imperfect specimens (1899, 1901, 1912-1915). (Box 40 of 44)
    - List of numbers of plants from the Herbarium of the East India Company (Box 40 of 44)
    - Chickering, John W. Jr. Herbarium (1944). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Request for herbarium cases to accommodate bamboo material (1944). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Furniture and Equipment Requests (1916-1946) (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Correspondence on Conzatti Herbarium (1931-1932). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Correspondence on Greene Herbarium (1914-1915). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Correspondence on Buchtien Herbarium (1921-1922). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Correspondence on Philippine Herbarium (most of the papers are with Mr. Coville) (1914-1927). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Thornber, J. J. Acknowledgment for gifts given to the National Museum; R. Rathbun (1906). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Exchanges - Chicago Natural History and National Museum of Natural History (1960). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Smith, A. C. Answering letters about Yoco (1950-1951). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Smith, A. C. and E. P. Killip. Loans recalled (1938-1956). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Miscellaneous Articles on Various Plants (1943, 1967, 1971) (Box 40 of 44)
    - Killip, E. P. Berlin loans (1930-1939). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Annual report data and work plans for year (1948-1950). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Algae. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Hepatics. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Lichens. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Data in regard to specimens of the cryptogamic collections. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Exchanges with individuals: listing species (1949). (Box 40 of 44)
    - Examination and Reports (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Instructions for collecting lichens and diatoms. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Loans to SI (1948-1949) (Box 40 of 44)
    - Interdepartmental Loans (1948-1949) (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. and E. P. Killip. Memoranda on determined and undetermined specimens (1945-1950) (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Radio appearances, news releases, and popular lectures. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Llano, G. A. Scientific papers in manuscript. (Box 40 of 44)
    - Maxon, William R. Herbarium protection during World War II (1941-1943). (Box 40 of 44)
  - Box 41
    - Manuscripts and Notes (4 volumes) (Box 41 of 44)
  - Box 42
    - Memoranda - Administrative (1897-1930) (4 volumes) (Box 42 of 44)
  - Box 43
    - Memoranda- Administrative (1931-1938) (3 volumes) (Box 43 of 44)
    - Annual Reports (1913-1921) (1 volume) (Box 43 of 44)
  - Box 44
    - Rose's Research Notes (15 folders) (Box 44 of 44)
  - Oversize
    - Map of the south of Peru and part of Bolivia showing the Peruvian railway extending into Bolivia, 1913 (Accession 12-357) (Oversize)